VLADIMIR IVANOV

 $\overset{\text{\tiny (a)}}{\mathbb{D}}$ +7 (924) 320·09·34 | \bowtie person@v-u-ivanov.com $Vladivostok,\ Maritime\ Province,\ Russia$

SUMMARY

Practical engineer with a focus on the EECS. 3+ years of experience in designing of embedded systems. I have built own experience through hardware and software co-design. Strong skills in electrical engineering, computer science and research area. Looking for new career opportunities in a team of professionals with using of progressive technologies and tools. Main areas of interest are consumer electronics, robotics, automotive and game industry, medical equipment, telecommunication and networks. No blocking problems to work outside the current location.

EDUCATION

Far Eastern State University, Vladivostok

August 2005 – June 2010

M.S. Departments of General Physics and Electronics.

Degree work was defended in the underwater robotics area.

GPA: 3.63 out of 4.

Secondary school 51, Vladivostok

September 2003 – June 2005

Secondary education.

In-depth study of Japanese Language.

Secondary school 51, Vladivostok

September 1995 – June 2003

General education.

In-depth study of Japanese Language.

SERTIFICATES

- Two-month course "6.00.1x: Introduction to CS and Programming". Excellent passing grade. The online learning initiative of Harvard University and MIT, December 2013.
- Three-month course "6.002x: Circuits and Electronics". Maximum passing grade. The online learning initiative of Harvard University and MIT, June 2012.
- Course of Japanese Language. The course of 1150 hours and a number of final exams. Secondary school 51 of Vladivostok, 1995 2005.

PUBLICATIONS

• Ivanov V. "The diagnostic system of a motor drive module for a underwater robot". Master thesis. Institute of Marine Technology Problems FEB RAS, Vladivostok, June 2010.

EXPERIENCE

Rhonda Software Ltd.

October 2012 – present

Vladivostok, RUS

Embedded Software Engineer

- · CSR plc. contractor. Work on the COACHTM SoC *imaging* platform.
- · Distributed supporting of the embedded software for ODM/OEM customers: main brand-manufacturers of imaging devices (digital still cameras, mobile driver recorders, action cameras, etc).
- · Support offices are located in a number of countries: China, Israel, Japan, Russia, South Korea, US.
- · Solving of time-critical project issues under a customer's pressure. Resolved a number of various "MP block" software and hardware problems.

- Supported peripheral domain. CMOS/CCD optic sensors: drivers bug-fixing, implementation of new capabilities, support for smear correction driver owners. NVM storages: filesystem bug-fixing, NAND drivers timing-optimizations. Display claster: problems related to video output (LCD, HDMI). Volatile-memory storages: DRAM performance measurement and timing-optimizations. On-chip peripheral: bug-fixing for usual BSP device driver set (GPIO, ADC, PWM, RTC, SPI, I2C, function-specific HW units and more). PC-side applied software: bug-fixing and new features implementation for firmware burning tool. Various peripheral-specific algorithms: e.g. Dynamic Voltage Management based on PID-controller. Improved processing performance of UI images for customer's projects.
- · Business trip to CSR Israel (formerly Zoran Corp.): MATAM, Advanced Technology Center, Haifa.

Spider Pacific Ltd.

Embedded Systems Engineer

October 2010 – October 2012 Vladivostok, RUS

- · Startup for a development of an applied hardware.
- \cdot Designed maket of the mechanical-less manipulator as part of the project management software system.
- · Designed and manufactured prototype of the valve tubes amplifier for a PC sound cards.
- · Designed and manufactured "Power over Ethernet" injector. Implemented physical layer of the IEEE 802.3af standart. The product was used in a number of computer network projects.

SKILLS

SW-Development	Embedded C and C++: source code mixing, a bit of STL. Interrupt- and event-driven design. Development process automation: Python and Perl. Build system: Make and WAF. Multi-threading; Atomthreads, ThreadX. Device drivers. Version control: Perforce, SVN, Git. Code review: Review Board, Code Collaborator. Issue tracking: JIRA, Redmine, eTraxis. Code documentation: Doxygen. Continuous integration: QuickBuild.
HW-Development	Digital/analog/tube circuits design and analysis: electrical and thermal calculations, circuits emulation. Selection of electronic components: excellent guided both in through-hole and surface-mount packages. Routing and assembling of prototype PCBs: Eagle CAD, Sprint Layout, a bit of Altium Designer. Excellent skills in manual soldering.
Debugging	Crash-logs analyzing. Remote debugging: customer support via e-mail threads and Skype. In-circuit emulation: JTAG. Lab-equipment usage: digital power supply, multimeter, analog/digital oscilloscope, signal generator, autotransformator.
Languages	English: professional working proficiency 日本語: elementary proficiency Russian: native
Misc	Foundations of project management: Spider Project. Lathe and milling works: Proxxon equipment. Bring up of computer networks: OSI. A bit experience in transferring of knowledges to students: electronics and

KEYWORDS

1-Wire, ADC, Altium Designer, Atomthreads, AVR, Bash, BSP, C, C++, CAN, Code Collaborator, cross-compiler, Cygwin, DAC, device driver, Doxygen, Eagle CAD, Eclipse, eTraxis, FAT, FileX, Gerber, Git, GNU toolchain, G-Sensor, gyro sensor, HW/SW co-design, IEEE 802.3af, I2C, JIRA, JTAG,

programming foundations.

KiCAD, libpng, Linux, Make, Maxima, MCS-51, MIPS, OOP, optic sensor, OSI, Perforce, Perl, PHP, PIC, Proxxon, Python, QuickBuild, R&D, Redmine, RS-232, RTOS, SPI, SPICE, Spider Project, RAW Bayer, Review Board, Source Insight, Sprint Layout, SQL, STL, SVN, TEX, ThreadX, UART, UML, USB, V8, Visual Studio, WAF, Windows, zlib

HOBBY AND INTERESTS

- · Hi-Tech and impacting one on a human being, designing hardware and software
- · Physics (two completed university years), applied math, world economic
- · Professional sports leagues: NHL, NFL, MLB
- · Swimming (sports category), marine multiathlon (sports category)
- · Cooking, electronic music